<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity on Shubham Malaviya</title><link>/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on Shubham Malaviya</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Impulse in the Clickstream -Behavioral Insights from Browsing History</title><link>/engineering/impulsive_behavior_modeling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engineering/impulsive_behavior_modeling/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-can-we-detect-risky-user-behavior-before-a-phishing-attack-succeeds"&gt;🚩 Can we detect risky user behavior before a phishing attack succeeds?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper tackles a fundamental but often overlooked problem in modern AI pipelines: annotation errors and their cascading impact on model training, evaluation, and human-in-the-loop data cleaning systems. &lt;br&gt;
In this research, we introduce a behavioral framework to detect and quantify impulsive clicks at the session level, revealing when users are momentarily vulnerable and how that vulnerability evolves across browsing contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unmasking Label Errors: Why Cybersecurity Benchmarks Need Stronger Benchmarks</title><link>/engineering/label_error_ccs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/engineering/label_error_ccs/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="-what-if-your-benchmark-is-wrong-and-your-best-model-only-looks-good-because-of-it"&gt;🧪 What if your benchmark is wrong and your best model only looks good because of it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work exposes a critical but underappreciated issue in cybersecurity research: annotation errors in benchmark datasets, particularly in evaluation (test) splits. The study shows that even modest label noise can severely distort model rankings, evaluation metrics, and research conclusions.&lt;br&gt;
By carefully curating a widely used CTI dataset and re-evaluating modern language models, this work argues for a fundamental shift toward robust, community-validated cybersecurity benchmarks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>